<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Office 365 on Office 365 blog</title>
    <link>http://o365blog.com/tags/office-365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Office 365 on Office 365 blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://o365blog.com/tags/office-365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep-dive to Azure Active Directory Identity Federation</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/aad-deepdive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/aad-deepdive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Identity federation is regarded as the most secure way to authenticate users to Azure AD. In this blog, I’ll deep-dive to identity federation implementation of Azure AD and point out some serious security issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create over 256 character long passwords for cloud-only users</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/long-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/long-passwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft (finally!) announced in April 2019 the support for 8-256 character passwords in Azure AD/Office 365.
This limit does not apply to users whose passwords are synced from the on-prem Active Directory (or for federated users).
In this blog, I tell how to set insanely long passwords (64K+) also for cloud-only users!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical deep dive to Microsoft Teams (free)</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/teams-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/teams-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Teams has been available for free since July 2018. In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll deep dive to its technical details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use a non-routable on-premises UPN with Office 365 and Azure AD</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/non-routable-upn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/non-routable-upn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently noticed that many organisations moving to Office 365 are struggling with their current on-premises non-routable UPNs. In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to use Office 365 without altering on-premises UPNs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing the Unicorn: PowerShell module for &#39;The Secret Office 365 Forensics Tool&#39;</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/exomailactivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/exomailactivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In June 2018 the existence of secret Office 365 forensics tool was confirmed.
The tool refers to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s undocumented Exchange Online Activities API.
The API provides access to a granular mail activity events for up to six months old data!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To provide administrators with easy access to the API, I created a PowerShell module (EXOMailActivity).
In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use the module to get access to mail activity data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Admin: Take back control of Office 365 Groups, Teams, and Planner!</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/limit-o365-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/limit-o365-groups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Office 365 groups is a great way to promote collaboration between people inside and outside organisations.
By default, users are able to create groups freely, making their use easy. However, in many organisations, this has led to chaos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I show how you can get back the control of Office 365 groups, Teams and Planner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to preserve user&#39;s mailbox during the long leave</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/inactive-mailboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/inactive-mailboxes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever faced a situation, where a user takes a longer than 30-day leave, and you would like to
save money spent on Office 365 licenses but still preserve user&amp;rsquo;s mailbox?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I tell you how!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office 365 email encryption</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/encrypt-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/encrypt-email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It still surprises me how few know that Office 365 includes a full-fledged email encryption solution, Office Message Encryption (OME).
A &amp;ldquo;new OME&amp;rdquo;, built on top of Azure Information Protection, has been available for some time now. In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how to setup and customise the new OME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is my Office 365 GDPR compliant?</title>
      <link>http://o365blog.com/post/o365-gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://o365blog.com/post/o365-gdpr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In short, no it&amp;rsquo;s not. In this blog, I’ll tell you three reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>